Hello, this is JB.
I'm with Austin Home Brew Supply here in Austin, Texas, and today we are talking about wine making equipment.
And specifically right now I want to talk about degassing your finished wine.
When you're making wine, one of the things that will happen at the end of the fermentation process is there'll be a lot of dissolved gas in the wine.
Now, as you know, when you serve a bottle of still wine--we're not talking about sparkling, we're not talking about champagne, we're talking about standard still wine, chardonnay, Cabernet sauvignon, what have you, there shouldn't be any dissolved gas within this wine once it's bottled.
So, as a home wine maker, you need to dry that gas out of the finished product before you put it into bottles.
How do you do that?
There's a few different techniques.
I'm going to show you the basic techniques.
The most basic of techniques is to simply use a spoon like this to degas the wine.